var questionsList = [
  {
    //research unit
    Question: "Bob performed an experiment on the relationship between sleep and productivity. Bob's results showed that as sleep went up, productivity went up. Which of the following is NOT an accurate statement?",
    A: "Sleep and Productivity have a positive correlation",
    B: "Poor sleep causes a decrease in productivity",
    C: "The amount of sleep is the independent variable",
    D: "No conclusion can be drawn from his data",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "John wants to perform an experiment on children, but does not give them full details of the experiment. Which of the following ethical laws is John violating?",
    A: "Deception",
    B: "Informed consent",
    C: "Debrief",
    D: "Protection of Participants",
    ANS: "A",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following components of an experiment is used in order to control the confounding variables?",
    A: "Random sampling",
    B: "Operational definitions",
    C: "Debriefing",
    D: "Random assignment",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following best explains why researchers define operational definitions?",
    A: "To following ethical laws of Psychology",
    B: "To make sure the participants are unaware of the experimental group",
    C: "To ensure that the experiment is reproducable ",
    D: "To see how a placebo can impact the results of the control group",
    ANS: "C",
  },
  {
    Question: "Sara created a survey to see how many hours of sleep a high school student gets every night. So far, she has surveyed 5 people and here are the results: 5 hours, 7 hours, 8 hours, 6 hours, and 4 hours. Calculate the mean.",
    A: "5",
    B: "6",
    C: "7",
    D: "8",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "Ricky is curious about whether or not students perform better on tests if they are chewing gum while taking the test. Which of the following research methods should Ricky perform?",
    A: "Case Study",
    B: "Survey",
    C: "Experiment",
    D: "Longitudinal Study",
    ANS: "C",
  },
  //social psych unit
  {
    Question: "Christina begins to like rap music after listening to it on the radio for numerous days. Which of the following explains the reason for Christina to like rap?",
    A: "Serial position effect",
    B: "Mere exposure effect",
    C: "Halo effect",
    D: "Just world phenomenon",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "After acing a test, Randy begins to flaunt how smart and intelligent he is. However, after getting a 0, he blames his teacher and school. Which of the following explains Randy's behavior",
    A: "Fundamental attribution error",
    B: "Social Loafing",
    C: "Ingroup/Outgroup bias",
    D: "Self-serving bias",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
    Question: "The tendency to act reserved and cautious in group situations while discussing conflict in order to maintain harmony is known as",
    A: "Social facilitation",
    B: "Social loafing",
    C: "Groupthink",
    D: "Group polarization",
    ANS: "C",
  },
  {
    Question: "Eric is a reserved and shy student. He tries to be nice to people around him and respects his teachers. However, online, Eric rants on social media and is critical to almost everyone. Which of the following explains Eric's change in behavior?",
    A: "Group polarization",
    B: "Deindividualization",
    C: "Just world phenomenon",
    D: "Halo effect",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "Jodi is usually a well-performing student, but when she is with her friends, she goofs off and does not do work. Which of the following best explains Jodi’s behavior?",
    A: "Social inhibition",
    B: "Social loafing",
    C: "Just world phenomenon",
    D: "Self-serving bias",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "Pat is walking down a crowded street and sees a man trip over and drop his belongings. However, Pat does not offer to help and continues walking. Which of the following explains why Pat does not help the man.",
    A: "Bysander effect",
    B: "Groupthink",
    C: "Social facilitation",
    D: "Law of effect",
    ANS: "A",
  },
  //biological basis of behavior unit
  {
   Question: "You are walking around a park and you see a bear. Your pupils begin to dilate and your heart rate increases. Which of the following contributes to your response?",
    A: "Sympathetic nervous system",
    B: "Parasympathetic nervous system",
    C: "Hippocampus",
    D: "Pineal gland",
    ANS: "A",
  },
  {
   Question: "This system in the brain plays a major role in developing memories and learning",
    A: "Ocipital lobe",
    B: "Hippocampus",
    C: "Medulla",
    D: "Parasympathetic nervous system",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
   Question: "The Broca’s and Wernicke’s area are areas of the brain that help with language production and comprehension. When the Wernicke’s area, in particular, is damaged, which of the following disorders is associated with this damage?",
    A: "Obsessive-compulsive disorder.",
    B: "Bipolar disorder",
    C: "PTSD  ",
    D: "Aphasia",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
   Question: "Tom is a high school teenager who makes rash decisions. Which of the following parts of the brain is not develoepd and explains Tom’s inability to make rational decision by himself?",
    A: "Frontal lobe",
    B: "Parasympathetic nervous system",
    C: "Medulla",
    D: "Pituitary gland",
    ANS: "A",
  },
  {
    Question: "This part of the brain is what connects the left and right hemisphere. Split brain patients ahve this severed to eliminate connection between the two hemispheres.",
    A: "Cerebellum",
    B: "Prefrontal cortex",
    C: "Reflex arc",
    D: "Corpus callosum",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Reticular Formation plays an important role in the consciousness and arousal. If this were to be damaged, then a patient could be at risk of",
    A: "Moving during REM Sleep",
    B: "Not being able to form memories",
    C: "Being put in a Coma",
    D: "Loss of hearing",
    ANS: "",
  },
  //cognitive psych unit
  {
   Question: "Frank is an employer who wants to hire new employees. Frank wants to test the employees’ current ability and individual skills. Which of the following assessments should Frank use to determine who to hire?",
    A: "Aptitude test",
    B: "Standarized test",
    C: "Diagnostic test",
    D: "Achievement test",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
   Question: "Jake takes a personality test which tells him he is a extroverted, social person. However, Jake takes the same test 2 days later and the test tells him that he is reserved and shy. Due to Jake’s difference of scores, which of the following best explains what the test is lacking?",
    A: "Validity",
    B: "Operational definitions",
    C: "Reliability",
    D: "P-value",
    ANS: "C",
  },
  {
   Question: "Tim is extremely hungry and thirsty, so he goes to the grocery store to buy food and water. Which of the following theories of motivation is Tim most likely following?",
    A: "Incentive theory",
    B: "Drive reduction theory",
    C: "Instinct theory",
    D: "Optimal arousal theory",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
   Question: "During a test, Jim’s arousal must be maintained in order to do well. Jim can’t  be too nervous or excited about the test and he also can’t be too relaxed during the test. Which of the following theories of motivation explains how Jim’s performance is correlated with his arousal?",
    A: "Optimal arousal theory",
    B: "Drive reduction theory",
    C: "Incentive theory",
    D: "Hierarchy of needs",
    ANS: "A",
  },
  {
   Question: "Kate’s friend, Bob, whispers to her during a test and asks if she can tell him the answer to question 5. Kate, however, refuses because she believes that cheating is not right and is looked down upon in society. Which of the following stages of Kohlberg’s Cognitive Moral Development model explain Kate’s thought process?",
    A: "Preconventional",
    B: "Conventional",
    C: "Postconventional",
    D: "None of the above",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
   Question: "Harry Harlow’s research on attachment using monkey showcased that monkeys",
    A: "Do not show and signs of separation anxiety when they are away from their mothers	",
    B: "Will not eat if their mother is not next to them",
    C: "Prefer mothers that provide food over comfort",
    D: "Prefer mothers that provide comfort over food",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  //psych names
  {
    Question: "This person performed an experiment known as the Little Albert Experiment and discovered the classical conditioning principles and the generalization of fear.",
    A: "Jean Piaget",
    B: "Ivan Pavlov",
    C: "Harry Harlow",
    D: "John Watson",
    ANS: "D",
  },
  {
    Question: "This German psychologist is known as the father of Psychology, being the founder of the first psychology laboratory.",
    A: "Sigmund Freud",
    B: "Little Albert",
    C: "Wilhelm Wundt",
    D: "John Locke",
    ANS: "C",
  },
  {
    Question: "This psychologist performed an experiment on college students and created a mock prison to see how the students would play their roles.",
    A: "John Locke",
    B: "Philip Zimbardo",
    C: "Wilhem Wundt",
    D: "Stanley Milgram",
    ANS: "B",
  },
  {
    Question: "This psychologist is known as the founder of psychoanalysis and explained psychology through the unconscious mind.",
    A: "Wilhem Wundt",
    B: "Solomon Asch",
    C: "Sigmund Freud",
    D: "Jean Piaget",
    ANS: "C",
  },
];
